原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     折千纸鹤的小熊    米帅家的薇薇安
翻译     Alex   姚老师越狱实验室
翻译     ABC的母上大人爱看越狱    肉塔
翻译     高庭玫瑰   PiPi
翻译     徐棒棒    木浅
校对     木浅    普利星布里狗
校对     不上课的匡老师是越狱老司机
校对     不高兴抱走米胖胖
校对     何何也爱折千纸鹤
校对     冰卡
时间轴    姜姜不打胰岛 浪影书构狐狸河 全身纹大葱
WEB版    时间轴   何何也爱折千纸鹤
后期     小海
精校     何何也爱折千纸鹤
总监     何何也爱折千纸鹤
最新海外影视剧下载
人人词典
使用人人词典查词学习，美剧原声朗读与例句场景
Prison Break
微信扫描
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔
《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break...
迈克尔·J·斯科菲尔德
1974年10月8日-2010年11月4日
丈夫  父亲  兄弟  叔叔  朋友
欲变世界  先变其身
失去兄弟  仿佛生活中出现一个巨大的空洞
Losing a brother, the massive hole that leaves in your life.
失去丈夫也一样
Like the same massive hole losing a husband makes.
你弟弟死了  林肯
Your brother's dead, Lincoln.
那你要怎么解释这个
How do you explain that?
-林肯·布鲁斯  -雅各布
- Lincoln Burrows. - ‭Jacob.
林肯伯伯
Uncle Lincoln!
911  我家有人持械入室
911. I have an armed intruder in my house.
我们触发了一些事
We've awoken something--
一些被极力掩盖的关于迈克尔的事
something people are trying to hide about Michael.
奥杰吉亚监狱
我都不知道我们在反击谁
I don't know who we're fighting.
我们去也门查清楚
Let's go to Yemen and find out.
你对也门一无所知
You don't know a damn thing about Yemen.
我会找到有门路的人
I'll find someone who does.
这个国家已支离破碎了  大家都想逃出去
The country's falling apart. Everyone wants out.
欢迎来到内战
Welcome to the civil war.
快来  否则我们都得死
Come quickly, or we'll all be dead!
-联络人是谁来着  -一个叫希巴的女人
- Who's that contact again? - A woman named Sheba.
迈克尔可能被卷入到什么严重的事情里了
Michael's caught in the middle of something big.
为"卡尼尔·乌提斯"度身定制
卡尼尔·乌提斯是个臭名昭著的恐怖分子
Kaniel Outis is a big-time terrorist.
我们已经安排了一次到奥杰吉亚监狱的探视
We've arranged a visit to Ogygia Prison.
意思是  迈克尔在那里吗
That mean Michael's in there?
迈克尔
Michael?
我的名字不叫迈克尔  我也不知道你们是谁
My name isn't Michael, and I don't know who you are.
狱卒  带我回牢房
迈克  你在干什么  该死的
Mike, what are you doing, damn it?!
随着ISIL恐怖组织越发逼近首都
The fighting in Yemen intensified today
今天也门的战况也愈演愈烈
as ISIL forces get ever nearer to the capital.
叛军声称其意图接管这个国家
The rebels, who have the stated intent of taking over the country
并建立一个激进的"哈里发"国[伊斯兰教王权或辖地]
and establishing a radical caliphate,
同时决心要解救其领导人阿布·拉马尔
are also bent on freeing their leader, Abu Ramal,
此人于五年前被政府俘获
who was captured by the government five years ago.
拉马尔以其极端的观点和做法而闻名
Ramal is known for his extreme views and practices,
从用少女当性奴隶
from using young girls as sex slaves,
到打着中世纪正义的标签
to a medieval brand of justice
包括当街公开施行斩首和处决
that includes public beheadings and executions in the street.
拉马尔目前被关在
Ramal is currently being held in
也门臭名昭著的监狱  奥杰吉亚监狱
Yemen's most notorious penitentiary, Ogygia Prison.
也门  奥杰吉亚监狱
时机到了
This is it.
维普  上来
Whip, get up here.
现在就行动了吗
Is it happening?
你不会丢下我们的  对吧
You are not going to leave us, are you?
如果叛军占领这座城市  我们就死定了
If the rebels take the city, we're dead.
你已经跟我们唠叨一千遍了  希德
You've told us that a thousand times, Sid.
你都成唐僧了  安全了吗
You're a broken record. Is it clear?
好的  安全了
Okay, it's clear.
维普  拿着
Whip. Come on.
熄灯后  你跟上
Lights go out... ...you follow.
快点
Come on.
要是像以前一样
Would have made it so much easier
只有你我不是要容易得多吗
if it was just you and me like it was on all the other ones.
这次没那么容易
Nothing is easy on this one.
可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
等等
One minute.
木板横在缺口处
Board spans the gap.
好的
Okay.
毯子盖住铁丝网
Blanket covers the wire.
现在就等那些灯熄了
Now it's about those lights going out.
二十四小时前他没有闪灯
He didn't flash it 24 hours before.
-那本来是信号  -要有信心
- That's supposed to be the signal. ‭- Have faith.
连着七个晚上吗
Seven straight nights?
没有信号  灯从来没熄过
No signal, no lights getting turned out?
那些攻击也越来越近了
Those strikes are getting closer, too.
那些灯不会熄了
Those lights aren't going out.
-灯不会熄了  -得回去了
- Lights aren't going out. ‭- Got to go back.
不如试试直接跑
Maybe make a run for it.
距离太远了[变数太多]
Too much ground to cover.
我们到不了缺口就会被射杀
They'll shoot us down before we make the gap.
那你怎么打算  坐以待毙吗
What's the plan then? Give up and die?
我可不能再等上四年了
I can't wait another four years.
本来说好只有一周的
It was supposed to be one week.
波塞冬把我们丢在这里等死
Poseidon has left us here to die. ‭
我们还有一步棋可以走
We still got one card left to play.
我本来不想这么做  但它已经开始了
I didn't want to play it, but it's already in motion.
我们走吧
Let's go.
卡尼尔·乌提斯显然是因为对抗政府
Apparently, Kaniel Outis was thrown into Ogygia
而被投进奥杰吉亚监狱
for crimes against the government.
不久以后  他因为企图逃跑
Shortly after, he was captured
被抓住  之后关了禁闭
trying to escape, and thrown into solitary.
他们最近刚释放他回囚区
They just released him into gen pop recently.
叫他迈克尔  行吗
Call him Michael, will you?
那为什么他见到我们时不肯认我们
But why didn't he acknowledge us when he saw us?
站住
Stop!
给我回来
Get back here!
-那孩子在监视我们  -是的
- Kid was spying on us. - Yeah.
他还在门垫下面留了个东西
And he left something under the doormat.
找到光之酋长
我就会重获自由
这是迈克尔的笔迹
This is Michael's handwriting.
天鹅是他的标志  他想联系我们
Swan was his calling card. He's reaching out to us.
但他干嘛搞得这么神秘
But why is he being so mysterious?
以前  他有没有说话这么拐弯抹角
Back in the day, he never talked to you straight,
到了用暗号的程度
as in not in code?
他是担心有人会拦截他的信息
He's worried about someone intercepting his message.
好吧  但这信息是什么意思
Yeah, but what does it mean?
我不知道  但他期望我们知道
I don't know, but we're supposed to know.
光之酋长  光之酋长
"Sheik of Light." ‭Sheik of Light.
听起来像是那种在山顶上
That sounds like a guy on a mountain peak
和真主交流的人
communing with God.
我们得找人帮忙
Yeah, we got to get help.
-没人能帮我们  -希巴
- We're out of help. - ‭Sheba.
她认为我在帮助恐怖分子
She thinks I'm abetting a terrorist.
那你就得向她证明并非如此
Well, then you have to convince her that you're not.
您必须离开  爸爸
You have got to leave, Papa.
-我不会逃跑的  -政府正遭到攻击
- I will not run away. - The government is being targeted.
您也成了被攻击的对象
You are being targeted.
我是个无名小卒
I'm a no one.
您对他们来说等同于政府
You are government to them.
你不懂做一个也门人的意义
You don't understand being a Yemeni.
在祖国最需要你的时候  你会转身就跑吗
You would run away when she needs you the most?
我只知道我们死了对国家是毫无价值的
I understand that we are no good to this country dead.
爸爸  留得青山在  不怕没柴烧
Papa, there will come a time.
我们逃去海外  和流亡政府一起重整旗鼓
We go abroad, regroup with an exile government.
哪有钱供我们逃呢  孩子
With what money, girl?
得花费两年的工资啊
It would cost two years' salary.
我宁可直面敌人而死  也不愿当逃兵
I'd rather die with my face to the enemy than to run away.
爸爸
Papa...
我建议你尽快离开这个国家
I suggest you leave this country as quickly as you can.
他来干嘛
What's he doing here?
我朋友需要你的帮忙
My friend needs your help.
我给过他帮助了
I gave him my help.
你却没告诉我  他与我们的敌人勾结
You didn't tell me he was working with the enemy.
这个你声称是你弟弟的男人
This man you claim is your brother,
卡尼尔·乌提斯  和叛军勾结
Kaniel Outis, worked with the rebels.
-他叫迈克尔·斯科菲尔德  -关我屁事
- His name's Michael Scofield. - I don't care!
不是卡尼尔·乌提斯
Not Kaniel Outis!
现在不管你说什么
There's nothing you can say to me
我都不会帮你  好吗
that will make me help you, okay?
是吗
Is that right?
这些足够带你全家离开这个国家了吧
This enough to get your family out of the country?
先给我办这件事
Deliver me this first.
找到光之酋长
我就会重获自由
纽约州  伊萨卡
准备好了吗  宝贝
Ready, love?
我们昨天在奥杰吉亚监狱录下了这个
- 林肯
-那是什么  -这是...
- What's that? - It's, uh...
这是你林肯伯伯发来的东西
It's something your Uncle Lincoln sent.
-来吧  -我不想去
- Here. ‭- I don't want to go.
我想和你在一起
I want to stay with you.
你得去上学
You got to go to school.
下课的时候  我会在这里等着你
And I'm gonna be right here when the bell rings.
好吗  你从台阶上走下来
Okay? You walk down those steps,
直接上车  好吗
you hop straight into the car. Yeah?
我爱你
I love you.
祝你上学愉快
Make it a great day.
我收到你的消息了
I got the note.
我收到了  迈克尔
I got the note, Michael.
我们会把你救出来的
We're going to get you out of here.
听着  我不叫迈克尔
Look, my name isn't Michael,
我也不知道你是谁
and I don't know who you are.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
雅各布·奈斯
你知道我成了有名的经济学家吗
You know I'm a noted economist?
我是说  报纸上是这么写的
I mean, that's what it says in the paper.
"著名经济学家在家遇袭"
"Noted Economist Attacked in Home."
我都不知道经济学家都能上新闻
I didn't even know economists made the news.
但愿没有下次了
That's the first and last time, hopefully.
我一直想把这一切搞清楚
I've been trying to piece this thing together.
你还记得那些政府的人吗
You remember those government guys,
那些智囊团的家伙
those think tank guys,
想向我请教博弈论的东西
trying to pick my brain about game theory,
以及他们怎样才能把它用于外交政策上
how they could use it for foreign policy?
记得  他们烦透你了  对吗
Yeah, you bored the hell out of 'em, right?
对  但我的意思是
Yeah, okay, but I mean,
我是不是刚听到了什么不该听到的
did I hear something I shouldn't have?
我不知道啊  你有听到吗
I don't know. Did you?
比如谁刺杀了肯尼迪
Like who shot JFK?
我可是认真的
I am trying to be serious here.
不  你是不是止痛药吃多了
No, you're doped up on painkillers
是你想太多了
and you're thinking too much.
我保证这和你一点关系也没有
I promise this has nothing to do with you.
好好休息吧  我要去...
You rest. I'm going to, um...
我还有些事要办  然后我再去看你  好吗
I'm gonna run some errands, and then I'm gonna come visit you, okay?
好的  爱你
Okay. Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
结束通话
好了  没问题  谢谢
Okay, no problem. Thanks.
我之前打电话问起过一名在中东失踪的美国公民
I, uh, I called earlier about a missing U.S. Citizen in the Middle East.
没错  我是亨利·岸田
Yes. I'm Henry Kishida.
我带你去局长办公室
Let me walk you to the director's office.
这种情况不常见
It's an unusual situation,
你应该感到庆幸
which you can appreciate,
毕竟你丈夫在法律上已经宣告死亡
since your husband is declared legally dead,
而且你提到这个人
and the person that you're referring to
使用的是另一个名字
goes by another name.
这里交给我吧  亨利
I'll take it from here, Henry.
你好吗  莎拉
How are you, Sara?
凯勒曼
Kellerman?
你们谈吧  有什么需要叫我  长官
I'll leave you two be. Let me know if you need anything, sir.
抱歉  我怎么又和你扯上关系了
‭Sorry, how did I end up with you again?
你向国务院提出求助
You asked for the State Department's help.
我想要国务院的帮忙  不是你
I wanted the State Department, not you.
你以前的身份太过复杂
Yeah, you've lived so many lives,
不知道这次你扮演谁了
I don't know who you are.
你的处境不也一样吗  不是吗
That'd be a consistent theme for you, wouldn't it,
你嫁了一个根本不存在的男人
given that you were married to a man who never existed?
你这话是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是你该进来  我会把关于
It means you should come in and let me enlighten you
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的事都告诉你
to all things Michael Scofield...
或者该管他叫卡尼尔·乌提斯
Or should I say Kaniel Outis?
你不该喝瓶装水的
You shouldn't drink bottled water--
里面都是二恶英  双酚A...[两者都有致癌性]
the dioxins, the BPAs in there...
很感激你关心我
I'm touched by your concern.
请坐
Have a seat.
不用了  谢谢
Good, thank you.
你知道的  莎拉
You know, Sara...
你和我有段...  波折的过往
you and I have... a checkered past.
但我现在就是个无趣之人  而且...
But I am evermore a boring guy now, and...
被生活磨平了棱角  相信我
mellowed by life, trust me.
如果你有关于迈克尔的消息想告诉我
If you have something you want to tell me about Michael,
就赶紧说吧
I'd sure love to hear it.
好吧
Okay.
接到你的电话后岸田就进行了调查
When your call came in and Kishida processed it...
我就说些让我们甚为震惊的
well, let's just say there are certain keywords
关键词好了
that get our system buzzing pretty quickly.
卡尼尔·乌提斯...
Kaniel Outis...
其实  我实在受不了你用瓶子喝水
Actually, can't stand it watching you drink out of that.
岸田
Hey, Kishida?
能帮莎拉倒杯水吗
Could you bring Sara a glass for her water, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
卡尼尔·乌提斯...
Kaniel Outis...
是一名因杀害
is a known terrorist,
一名中情局高级官员
ties to ISIL, wanted in the killing
而被通缉的ISIL恐怖分子
of a senior CIA official.
迈克尔不会杀人的
Michael's no killer. ‭
这就是问题所在
You see, that's the problem.
因为卡尼尔·乌提斯会
Because Kaniel Outis is.
-谢谢  -不用谢
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
而且...
And...
这就是卡尼尔·乌提斯
this is Kaniel Outis.
简直荒唐
That's ridiculous.
卡尼尔·乌提斯  系ISIL恐怖分子
因杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
而被中情局  联调局通缉
官方记录显示...
The record here at State says that...
这张脸就是卡尼尔·乌提斯
that's Kaniel Outis's face.
好吧  但你我都知道迈克尔·斯科菲尔德是谁
‭Okay, but you and I both know who Michael Scofield was.
不  那只是回忆
No, that's just a memory.
官方记录  包括他的过去
The official record-- history--
都已经不同了
it says otherwise now.
你想想幕后主使  那才叫恐怖
Now, that's scary, to think who could be behind that.
因为只有那种非常厉害的角色
Because only somebody very formidable
才能做到
would be capable
在官方层面为一个人更改身份
of officially turning one man into another.
比如像迈克尔那样的天才
It would take a genius... like Michael.
你是在暗示这是他自己策划的吗
You're insinuating that he did this?
他消失了
He disappeared,
就这样放弃了他的生活吗
just quit on his life?
我和你一样想要知道答案
I want answers just like you do.
谁能办到这种事
Who's capable of this?
全世界能做到的人屈指可数
Only a handful of people in the world.
莎拉  莎拉
Sara? Sara!
我们应该还有一天
I figure we got a day,
顶多两天时间离开这鬼地方
maybe two, tops, to get out of this hole.
等到那时  我们要么是被炮弹炸死...
At that point, either the shelling gets us...
要么被ISIL的人干掉
or ISIL does.
你一点都不担心吗
Does any of this faze you at all?
我们马上就要死在这里了
The fact that we're gonna die in here?
我们不会死  我们还是会逃出去的
We're not gonna die. We're still getting out.
我们所有人
All of us.
怎么逃  通过房顶吗
How's that? The roof?
-房顶行不通的  -能行得通
- The roof ain't happening. - The roof is happening.
我们没有时间再想一套越狱方案了
We don't have time to come up with another escape plan.
所以你确实紧张了
So you are nervous.
好极了  现在我知道我在劫难逃了
Great, now I know I'm in deep crap.
找到光之酋长  我将重归自由
我做这些只是为了钱
I'm only doing this for the money.
别以为咱俩关系突然变好了
Don't think you and I are suddenly good.
你只管帮我找到酋长就行
You just deliver me the sheik.
酋长们离这里很远
The sheiks are well away from here.
在沙漠高原
High desert.
而且我从没听说过有叫光之酋长的
And I've never heard of one being referred to as Sheik of Light.
也就是说这可能是暗语
Which means it's probably a code.
她真了解你弟
She knows your brother.
这条纸带
This tape--
是唯一一个不属于这张纸的东西
it's the only thing that doesn't belong.
你弟弟喜欢说谜语  是不是
Your brother speaks in riddles, does he?
有可能是盲文  或者是摩尔斯码
‭Maybe it's Braille or, uh, Morse.
或者只是数字
Or just numbers.
我觉得是个电话号码
I think it's a phone number.
语音信箱
Voice mail.
穆罕默德·埃尔·突尼斯
Mohammad El-Tunis.
萨那的电气工程主任
Director of Electrical Works in Sana'a.
电气工程主任
Director of Electrical Works.
"光之酋长"
"Sheik of Light."
电气工程部
萨那
感谢您百忙之中来见我们
Thanks for taking the time to see us.
人都哪去了
Where is everybody?
他们事先就逃走了
They are fleeing ahead of the advance.
我们一直在找他
We have been trying to reach him.
我们只知道他去了郊区
All we know is that he went to the suburbs
去找他的女儿
to try to find his daughter.
你有她的地址吗
Do you have an address for her?
我们试着给她打过电话了  但是没人接
We tried calling her, but no answer.
这是地址
Address is here.
你们不会是想去找他吧
You are not going to try to find him, are you?
愿真主与你们同在
God be with you, then.
地址圈出来了
Circled the address.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
你跟我们一起走
You're coming with us.
如果你以为我会去郊区的话
If you think I'm going into the suburbs,
那你们就是疯了
you're crazy.
郊区怎么了
What's wrong with the suburbs?
郊区在那边
The suburbs are out there.
战争的前线
The front line of the war.
很高兴认识你  还有你本杰明
Nice knowing you, Benjamin.
我希望下次见面时  状况能好些
I hope next time it's under better circumstances.
-付钱吧  -你得带我们通过关卡
- Pay up. - You have to get us past the checkpoint.
我们俩美国人  没有你我俩啥都办不成
Two Americans-- we'll never make it without you.
我可不想自杀
I am not getting myself killed.
付钱
Pay up.
给我找到酋长
Deliver the sheik.
我就给你钱
Then you get your money.
上车
Get in.
喂
Yes?
看一下你的邮箱  莎拉
You should check your e-mail, Sara.
我看的这是什么
What am I looking at?
一个猎人四年前拍的照片
Footage captured by a hunter four years ago.
用一种挂在树上的运动传感器
One of those motion sensor devices you hang on trees,
可以间歇性拍摄猎物
takes intermittent photos of prey.
有一天早晨  猎人出门发现了这些图片
Hunter comes out one morning, finds these images.
这就是我跟你说的那起谋杀
This is the killing I was telling you about.
受害者是哈伦·盖恩斯  中情局副局长
The victim's Harlan Gaines, Deputy Chief of the CIA.
而杀手...
And the killer...
你也看到了
well, you can see,
就是被我们称为迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的人
it's who we call Michael Scofield,
或者卡尼尔·乌提斯
or Kaniel Outis, or...
当初他们对林肯用的也是这招
This is exactly what they did to Lincoln.
第二天就有血迹证据了
And then there's the blood evidence the next day.
卡尼尔或者迈克尔上了去也门的飞机
Kaniel or Michael or whatever gets on a flight to Yemen.
他下飞机时  我们差点就抓住他了
We all most nail him when he lands.
但跑了和尚跑不了庙  他的行李还在
He gets away. His luggage doesn't
里面的衣服上全是盖恩斯的血
and Gaines' blood is all over the clothes inside.
证据确凿
The evidence is overwhelming.
不论你想叫他什么名字
Whatever name you want to call him,
迈克尔都是凶手  萨拉
Michael's a murderer, Sara.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
你还好吗
You all right?
这老习惯吗  嗯  我挺好的
This old thing? Yeah, I'm doing fine.
怎么了
What's going on?
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
但你可能不想谈论这件事
It's probably something you're not gonna want to talk about.
但我真的很需要你清晰的思路
I could really use your clarity right now.
事关迈克尔
It's about Michael.
我还是想知道他是怎么把这东西弄进来的
Still want to know how he got that in here.
跟狱警睡了
Hugging naked with the guards.
肯定的吧
Got to be, right?
那是什么
What the hell is that?
《我们是冠军》
"We are the Champions."
*我们是冠军*
*We are the champions*
你困在这么个厕所一样的地方  还看皇后乐队
You get stuck in a Porta-Potty like this, you go Queen?
怎么不看点女人自慰的小黄片呢
I mean, where are the girls riding the washing machines, right?
再看我的屏幕  我就用它戳瞎你的狗眼
Look at my screen again, this goes in your eye.
大千世界无奇不有
You know, the world never ceases to amaze.
被关在中东的监狱里
You get stuck in a Middle Eastern prison,
而里面最混蛋的却是个韩国棒子
the biggest S.O.B. is a Korean.
他停药后犯瘾了
He's in withdrawal.
*因为我们是*
*'Cause we are the champions*
*世界冠军*
*Of the world... *
知道吗  他是这世界上
You know, he's the biggest collector
最大的皇后乐队周边收藏家
of Queen paraphernalia in the world.
据说他首尔的家就是个佛莱迪·摩克瑞的神龛
They say his house in Seoul is a shrine to Freddy Mercury.
那他怎么被关进来的
And he got in here how?
身份盗窃
Identity theft.
显然他经常坐在自家沙发上
Apparently he used to sit on his couch,
黑进世界各国的高额网络账户
hack high net worth accounts all over the world.
然后用这些钱来收藏悍马车  直升机
Turned it into a collection of Hummers, helicopters
当然还有佛莱迪·摩克瑞的骨灰
and, apparently, Freddy Mercury's ashes.
等等  你是说他火化的骨灰吗
Wait, you mean like his burnt-up body?
据说佛莱迪被火化了  但骨灰却不见了
The story is Freddy's cremated, but his ashes go missing.
至今没有人知道下落
To this day no one knows where they are.
有一次雅嗑嗨了之后告诉我是他买下了
Ja admitted to me once when he was high he bought them.
两百万美金
Two million bucks.
皇后乐队的主唱都能在他家客厅里
He's got Queen's lead singer in his family room.
你是怎么知道这些的
How exactly do you know all this?
我问他的
I asked him.
他没犯瘾时  真的是个大好人
He's a real mensch when he's not in withdrawal.
我都不知道你跟他说过话
I didn't know you talked to him.
赞啊
Amazing.
我还以为我懂你了  原来我不懂
Just when I think I know your game, I don't.
你懂我的  维普
You know my game, Whip.
对  就是这一声"维普"
See, right there, "Whip."
我都不知道你为什么这么叫我
I don't even know why you call me that.
因为你是我的得力干将
Because you're my whip hand.
我的王牌
My ace in the hole.
好吧
Yeah, sure, okay.
在博弈论中  你需要成为两面派
See, in game theory, it serves you to be two-faced.
和每个人做朋友  直到你再不需要为止
Be everyone's friend till the moment you're not.
你要让大家都爱你至深  在关键时刻
You make them love you so much that when they're up against it,
朋友间的义气会让他们
their loyalty will make them act
做出违背自己最高利益的事情
against their own best interests.
这就是博弈论
That's game theory.
冷静  理智  专注于赢
A cold, rational focus on winning.
尽管需要牺牲其他所有人
Even if it's at everyone else's expense.
我想知道的是他想得到什么
What I'm trying to understand is what he stands to gain.
离开他的家人  用新的身份生活
Leaving his family, and-and the new identity.
从你告诉我的那点事来看  他变了
According to the little you've told me, he was different.
他总是有自己的小算盘  不是吗
Always an agenda, right?
是
Yeah.
他显然很爱你
I mean, he apparently loved you.
他当然爱你了
Of course he loved you.
他怎么会不爱你呢
How could he not?
但他也想要你为他打开监狱的那扇门
But he also wanted you to open that door in the prison for him.
在真正的博弈论中
I mean, true game theory,
任何事  任何人
everything, everyone
都是一个偶然事件
is a contingency.
你会遇见别人  把他们带入自己的生活
You meet people, you bring them into your life
你会和他们一直搞好关系
and you keep them percolating until the moment
直到需要为自己而利用这些关系的那一刻
you need to manipulate the relationship to your advantage.
我不是在评判他  我不是那样的人
I'm not judging, you know? That's not my thing.
-我知道  -你了解我的  但是...
- I know. - You know me. But...
陷得太深
...schema as deep
算得太深  到最后
and as calculating as that can, in the end,
会把人逼疯
spin a man off into madness.
最开始他可能觉得为了顾全大局
He might initially think smaller evils are okay
可以纵容小恶
in the service of a greater good.
比如帮林肯越狱
Like breaking Lincoln out of prison.
不过善与恶有时难以分辨
But the dance of good and evil could become jumbled,
以至对他人的操控
and the manipulation itself
成了最重要的事
becomes the most important thing.
人会变得一心求胜
Becomes about winning
而不去考虑胜利本身是对是错
rather than whether the game should be won at all.
我从未见你这样害怕过
I don't think I've seen you this scared before.
他们说  这次"斋月"为示宽恕
They say, for Ramadan, as an act of forgiveness,
[伊斯兰教历的九月  该月内伊斯兰教徒每日从黎明到日落禁食]
他们要把那里面
they're going to release all prisoners
所有被禁闭的囚犯都释放到囚区
from solitary over there back into general population.
他们是最穷凶极恶之徒
Worst of the worst.
ISIL恐怖组织的狂热分子
ISIL fanatics.
阿布·拉马尔
Abu Ramal.
你知道他们会杀了我的
They're going to kill me, you know.
我因为是同性恋
Government gave me 20 years
被政府判了二十年
for homosexuality.
但是那里面的魔鬼
But the monsters in there,
拉马尔和他的手下
Ramal and his men,
不会让我活过二十分钟
won't let me live 20 minutes.
拜托告诉我
Please tell me
你仍然打算把我们弄出这个地方
you still plan on getting us out of here.
你当时负责熄灯
You were responsible for killing the lights,
而你的光之酋长却在关键时刻不知所踪
and then your Sheik of Light went missing at exactly the wrong time.
我不知道他发生了什么事
I don't know what happened to him.
也许我能想到别的办法
Maybe I can find another way.
有件事你倒是能做
There is something you could do.
给我一片口香糖
Give me a piece of that gum.
凭一片口香糖就能让我们越狱吗
Piece of gum is going to get us out of prison?
它将成为导火索
It'll start the process.
朋友  有时我都分不清
Sometimes, my friend, I can't tell which is bigger,
是你的计划更大还是你的谎言更大
your plans or your lies.
我可记住了  你说我是个骗子
I take that personally, you calling me a liar.
我会让你见识到  就像蝴蝶效应一样
And I'm gonna show you, just like the butterfly's wings,
这片口香糖会引发一系列事件
this piece of gum is gonna start a sequence of events
最终会让我们来到监狱高墙之外
that will finish on the other side of the world.
给我电池
Battery, please.
监狱版自制打火机
Prison lighter.
维普  我需要你的袜子
Whip, I need your socks.
希德  装水罐头
Sid, water can.
外面情况如何
How we doing out there?
没问题  动作要快
We're all good. Quick though.
好了
Okay.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure about this?
我们没有时间了
There's no time left.
这座城市快要沦陷了
The city's about to collapse.
非常时期  非常手段
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
好了
Got it.
快点  快点  快点
Come on, come on, come on.
快  快  快
Go, go, go.
狱警
Guards!
有人生病了
We got a sick one in here.
怎么回事
What is this?
他在发高烧  需要去趟医务室
He's burning up. He needs the infirmary.
拜托了
Please.
我们到了
This is it.
政府控制区边界
Limit of government control.
外面都是ISIL恐怖组织的领地
Anything after this is ISIL territory.
停车
Stop.
让我来谈
Let me do the talking.
他说我们是欧美人还有女人
He says us being Westerners, a woman...
一旦进去  就有去无回了
we go inside, we are not coming back.
他们不放我们通过
They're not letting us through.
告诉他  我赌500美金能安全返回
Tell him I bet $500 bucks we'll make it back in one piece.
他没有500美金来和你赌
He doesn't have $500 to bet.
不重要
It doesn't matter.
我们要是回不来  这钱就归他了
We don't make it back, he keeps it.
他说我们这是去送死
He says we have a death wish.
行吧
Fine.
这座城市曾经很美丽  充满生机
The city used to be beautiful, alive.
看看他们都干了什么
Look what they've done to it.
他们在到处张贴阿布·拉马尔的画像
They're putting up portraits of Abu Ramal.
他自从被关进奥杰吉亚监狱后
He's only gotten more powerful
就变得越来越有势力
since he got locked up in Ogygia.
他要是出狱了  我们就只能求真主保佑了
God help us if he gets out.
ISIL的人
ISIL.
我们的车会被拦下来  趴下
We're gonna get stopped. Get down.
快趴下
Down now.
藏好
Cover up.
停车
真不敢相信
Can't believe this.
我认识他
I know him.
身份证件
是你
雷扎
Reza.
现在是阿布·阿米尔
It's Abu Amir now.
你在城郊干什么  希巴
What are you doing in the suburbs, Sheba?
拐错弯了
Took a wrong turn.
你把头发罩起来了
You got your hair covered up.
很好
That's good.
终于找到真主了吗
Finally find God?
不是你的真主
Not your God.
世上只有一位真主
There is only one God.
我们会拿下这座城市  你知道的
We're gonna take the city, you know.
只要你乖乖的
You be nice...
或许我能让你成为一个好女人
maybe I'll make a good woman of you.
原谅你内心的魔鬼
Forgive the devil in you.
不如我现在就掉头
Why don't I just turn around now?
我们原谅彼此
We forgive each other.
忘记彼此的存在
Forget each other ever existed.
美人可不是那么轻易就被忘记的
Beauty is not so easily forgotten.
"万人迷"[绰号]
Lover boy!
我们得走了
We have to go.
政府军正逼近阿克萨公园
Government's moving in at Aksa Park.
给她放行
Cut her loose.
滚出我们的地盘
Get the hell off our territory.
他们走了
They are gone.
我们得赶快
We have to hurry.
他刚才没杀我  算我们走运
We're lucky he didn't kill me right then.
为什么
Why?
没准我将来会告诉你
Maybe I'll tell you one day.
他们正在摧毁我们的城市
They're destroying our city.
你的那些ISIL朋友正在摧毁我们的城市
Your ISIL friends are destroying our city.
而你现在却跑来寻求帮助
And you come in here wanting help.
随便给我点什么吧
Just give me a little something.
这里有医生吗  我在发高烧
Is there a doctor here? I'm burning up.
你早该想到会有今天了
You should have thought about that,
在你给他们提供武器的时候
when you supplied guns to them,
在你杀害那些好人的时候
assassinated good men.
那些指控是一场误会
Those charges were a misunderstanding.
真主啊
Oh, Allah.
卡尼尔·乌提斯说这是一场误会
Kaniel Outis says it was a misunderstanding.
那么你进监狱的那一刻
Was it also a misunderstanding
就在企图越狱
when you tried to escape
这是不是也是一场误会啊
the moment you got into this prison? Hmm?
诚实的人不会试图去越狱
An honest man doesn't try to escape,
而是会请律师
he asks for a lawyer.
但你自打进来的第一周就盘算着越狱
But you, you tried to escape the very first week.
要是我能做主  我会让你一辈子关禁闭
I'd have left you in solitary forever if it was up to me.
就是这个街区尽头的地址
The address at the end of the block.
是叛军
Rebels...
就在房子前面
right in front of the house.
这帮浑蛋
Son of a bitch.
在也门还有什么事是能轻松办到的
Anything easy in this country?
问题是  酋长究竟在不在里面
The question is: Is the Sheik even inside?
只有一个办法能找到答案
Only one way to find out.
要是在这上面被发现
‭They find us up here,
我们就没有解释的机会了
there's no explaining ourselves.
我们就死定了
We're all dead.
别出声
Quiet.
你们不是ISIL的人吗
You... You are not ISIL?
不  你是穆罕默德·埃尔·突尼斯  对吧
No. But you're Mohammad El-Tunis, I take it?
附近还有人
我们是从市中心来的
We are from the city center.
来救你出去
We are here to get you out.
除非让我女儿也一起走
Not without my daughter.
我们可以带上她  她人呢
We can bring her. Where is she?
-她就在外面  -哪里
- She's out there. - ‭Where?
在街对面那间学校的地窖里
In the basement of the schoolyard, across the street.
ISIL的人一来  她就被困在那里
Pinned since ISIL arrived.
我本想来救她出来
I came to get her out.
结果我也被困住了
And I got pinned, too.
林肯  恕我直言
I hate to say it, Linc,
但我估计我们也一起被困住了
but I think we might've just got pinned as well.
你没事吧
You okay?
你看着像想要挨几刀
You look like you could use a few sharp edges
直接升天的人
knocked off your world.
彼此彼此
You don't look so good yourself.
对于也门  你想了解些什么
Say what you want about Yemen,
给起药品来他们倒是不吝啬
they're not shy about prescriptions.
这可是好玩意儿啊  吗啡衍生物
It's the good stuff. Morphine derivative.
我要用你的手机和信用卡号
I need access to your cell phone and a credit card number.
干嘛
Why?
叫份披萨
I want to order a pizza.
有个后门通往学校
There's a back door, toward the schoolhouse.
跟我来
Come on.
太迟了
Too late.
去屋顶上
Go to the rooftops.
他们遍布在那辆路虎的四周
They're all over the Rover.
我们跑不到那里
We'll never get to it. ‭
我可以到那辆小货车上
I can get in that pickup,
冲出去制造骚乱
make a ruckus on my way out.
顺利的话  他们会把我团团包围
Any luck, they'll be all over me.
然后你们趁四周没人赶紧上路虎
Then you got a clean shot to the Rover.
走  快走
Go. Go!
没有女儿  我哪也不去
I'm not leaving without my daughter.
你们不懂ISIL的人渣会使出什么手段
You don't know what ISIL will do to her
来对付像她这种教女孩们读书的人
for educating those girls.
我会救她出来  我保证
I'll get her out, I promise.
-快走  -好  好
- Go! - Okay! Okay.
你父亲让我来的  我来救你出去
Your father sent me. I'm getting you out of here.
快出来  快出来
Come on! Come on!
趴下  别起来
Get down! Stay down!
他一定得成功
He's got to make it.
你必须成功  给点力啊
You know you got to make it. Come on.
他来了  他来了
There he is! There he is!
太他妈帅了
Yeah, baby!
不  情况不妙
Oh, no. This isn't good.
情况非常不妙
This isn't good.
政府设的关卡
This government checkpoint.
他们会误会我们是自杀式炸弹袭击者
They'll think we're suicide bombers.
我们得停车
We have to stop.
你他妈疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
别开枪
Don't shoot at us!
别开枪  别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
枪手  打那个枪手
趴下
Stay down!
我也很开心
I'm so happy, too.
抱歉
Forgive me, uh...
她们的父母都被杀害了
Their parents have been killed.
我正想办法怎么才能帮到她们
I'm trying to figure out how I can help them.
她们可以暂时留在这
They can stay here for now.
只要告诉我  你在奥杰吉亚都认识谁
As long as you tell me who you know in Ogygia,
还有他们为什么那么需要你
and why they want you so bad.
我只是个...
I'm a man with, uh...
"问题孩子"的父亲
troublesome children.
他们是很好的孩子
They're beautiful.
但可能对于这个国家来说太离经叛道了
But perhaps too modern for this country.
我女儿想要教女孩们读书
My daughter tries to educate girls.
而我儿子
And my son,
他爱上了一个男人
he falls in love with another man.
因此他被判了在奥杰吉亚服刑二十年
They gave him 20 years in Ogygia Prison.
几周前我去看他
I went to visit him a few weeks ago.
他说  可能有办法出去
He said, maybe there is a way out.
一个我能帮上忙的方法
A way I could help.
一个男人不能眼看着家人被杀
A man is not a man if he would let his family die.
你答应了帮他
You agreed to help him.
那怎么帮
How?
他说只要我能想办法让全城停电
He said if I could arrange a blackout,
他... 他认识的一个人就能帮他逃出来
he... he knew someone who could get him out.
是个美国人吗
An American?
不知道
I don't know.
我本应该在一周前就安排好
I-I was supposed to do this a week ago,
但我女儿又出了这状况
but then this happened with my daughter.
感谢真主  你们找回了我们
Thank God you found us.
现在还有时间来实施计划
There's still time to do it.
他们正在监狱里等你
They're waiting for you in there.
那我现在就得走了
Then I have to go now.
他说我要准确地
He said I was to give a signal
在停电前24小时  给他们发一个信号
exactly 24 hours before the blackout.
我会让电网跳闪两次
I will pulse the power grid twice.
恐怕这座城市撑不到24小时了
This city may not have 24 hours in it.
再见  小家伙们
Bye, guys.
拜拜
Bye.
天知道我看人有多么不准
God knows I'm no perfect judge of character,
但对迈克尔不会
but Michael?
要是他们说的有那么一点是真的...
If any of what they're saying is true...
所以还有很多细节需要核实  莎拉
So there's more to find out, Sara.
重要的是  不管结果如何
I mean, the important thing is that you are gonna survive this,
你都会度过这一关的
however it turns out.
而且我们会支持你的  好吗
And we're here for you. Okay?
-我们走吧  -谢谢
- Let's go. ‭- Thank you.
联系我  好吗
Call me, okay?
好
Yeah.
我能进去接一下麦克吗
Hey, can I just scoop Mike real quick?
所有孩子都出来了
All the kids have been released.
你没接到他吗
You don't have him?
麦克
Mike?
-我去这边找  -好
- I'll go this way. - ‭Okay, yeah.
麦克
Mike?
你看见麦克了吗
Have you seen Mike?
麦克
Mike!
你在...
There...
你在干什么  吓死我了
What are you doing? You scared me.
我在看那个人去哪了
I was looking for where the man went.
什么人  宝贝
What man, baby?
给我这个的人
The man that gave me this.
披萨外卖员
The pizza man.
The pizza man?
风暴即将至  众生须躲藏
迈克尔
Michael.
你陷入了什么麻烦呢
What are you into?
ISIL恐怖组织每时每刻都在逼近
ISIL is getting closer by the hour.
这里的叛乱者也都清楚
And the rebels in here know it.
等ISIL占领了这里  他们就会杀了我们
When they take over, they'll kill all of us.
异教徒  罪人  外国人
Infidels, the sinners, the foreigners.
感谢真主
Praise Allah.
有人找到了我的父亲
Someone found my father.
那意味着越狱开始了
Means the escape is on.
从现在起  24小时
24 hours from now.
但也许太迟了
But this may be too late.
"斋月"已经开始了
Ramadan has begun.
守卫要释放囚犯了
The guards are releasing the prisoners.
阿布·拉马尔和他的手下
Abu Ramal and his men,
他们会杀了我
they'll kill me.
还有你
And you.
终于见到你自由了  兄弟
可我们还没自由呢
你为我们安排好出去的路了吗
是的  就在明晚
越 狱 第五季第二集